https://www.bradford.co.uk/privacy-policy/

We want to give you the best service by using cookies. Carry on browsing if you’re happy with this, or
find out more.
X
Customer Support
Make Online Payment
Gifts By CategoryJewelleryWomen's Necklaces & PendantsWomen's RingsWomen's BraceletsWomen's WatchesWomen's EarringsWomen's BroochesMen's WatchesMen's Necklaces & PendantsMen's BraceletsMen's RingsPersonalised JewellerySilver JewelleryGold JewelleryDiamond JewelleryAshton-Drake Collectable DollsAshton-Drake Lifelike Baby DollsAshton-Drake So Truly Real® DollsAshton-Drake Silicone Baby DollsAshton-Drake Special Features DollsAshton-Drake Monkey DollsAshton-Drake Boy DollsAshton-Drake Child DollsAshton-Drake Doll AccessoriesAshton-Drake Bride DollsAshton-Drake Fantasy DollsAshton-Drake Fashion DollsHome DécorClocksLampsCollector PlatesSculpturesTable CentrepiecesCandle HoldersWall DecorTankards & SteinsPillows & CushionsPersonalised Home DécorMusic BoxesPersonalised Music BoxesDisney Music BoxesSnow Globes & Glitter GlobesDecorative FigurinesChristmas FigurinesElephant FigurinesAngel FigurinesMemorial FigurinesDisney FigurinesCat FigurinesAnimal FigurinesChristmas DécorTabletop Christmas TreesPre-lit Christmas TreesChristmas Figurines & SculpturesSnow Globes & Water GlobesChristmas OrnamentsChristmas WreathsChristmas VillagesChristmas Table CentrepiecesChristmas Tree DecorationsChristmas LanternsCommemorative CoinsSilver CoinsGold CoinsMilitary CoinsRoyal CoinsDisney Coins Football CoinsCoin SetsFirst Edition and World First CoinsCoin Display CasesClocksCuckoo ClocksMantel ClocksTabletop ClocksWall ClocksWatchesMen's WatchesWomen's WatchesApparel & AccessoriesTote BagsHandbagsPurses & WalletsUmbrellasFleeces & JacketsShoesMore Gifts & CollectablesMore GiftsCollector PlatesTeacups & SaucersTrain & Train AccessoriesCookie JarsBooksZippo LightersAshton-Drake DollsPersonalised GiftsJewelleryCollectable CoinsSilver CoinsGold CoinsMilitary CoinsRoyal CoinsDisney CoinsFootball CoinsCoin SetsFirst Edition and World First CoinsCoin Display CasesAll CoinsMonthly Coin OfferDisneyBest SellersChristmasGifts By ThemeBird CollectablesDisneyCinderella GiftsDisney Princesses GiftsFrozen GiftsMickey and Minnie GiftsTinker Bell GiftsWinnie The Pooh GiftsNightmare Before Christmas GiftsAlice In Wonderland GiftsSnow White GiftsLittle Mermaid GiftsFinding Nemo GiftsBeauty And The Beast GiftsDisney Christmas Trees & OrnamentsDisney FigurinesDisney ClocksDisney SnowglobesDisney HandbagsDisney JewelleryDisney WatchesDisney Character GiftsDisney Collectable GiftsRoyalPrince WilliamDuchess of CambridgePrincess DianaQueen Elizabeth IIPrince PhilipPrince HarryMeghan MarklePrince George of CambridgePrincess Charlotte of CambridgeQueen VictoriaPippa MiddletonRoyal Wedding 2018Flying ScotsmanMilitaryAirforceArmyNavyRoyal MarinesFirst World War (WWI)Second World War (WWII)StagsThomas KinkadeChristmas TreesChristmas OrnamentsRelationshipGifts For HerGifts For HimGifts For DaughtersGifts For SonsGifts For SistersGifts For GranddaughtersGifts For GrandsonsGifts For GrandmothersGifts For FathersGifts For MothersFor WifeFor HusbandElvis PresleyHarry Potter™COCA-COLA®Sci-FiStar Wars™STAR TREK™Aliens™More ThemesConcordeI Love You To The Moon And BackChristmasPatrioticBritainEnglandIrelandScotlandWalesReligionFloralPoppiesGarden FlowersIn Loving MemoryLest We ForgetIcons & EntertainmentElvis PresleyJohn WayneMarilyn MonroeBetty Boop™Star Wars™Music BandsHarry PotterBatman™IrishNative AmericanSportFootballTottenhamManchester CityAston VillaFulhamWest HamChelseaBowlsHorse RacingPetsCatsDogsShih TzuYorkieChihuahuaPomeranianPugSchnauzerDachshundWestieLabradorKing Charles SpanielPoodleBichon FriseBoston TerrierJack RussellGolden RetrieverMalteseBoxerBeagleCocker SpanielGerman ShepherdSheltieAngelsDragonsEgyptianFantasyDragonsFairiesWitchesJohn WayneLena LiuTrainsMotorcyclesFordSanta ClausSnowmenBirdsRobinBluetitsEaglesHummingbirdsOwlsAnimals & WildlifeBirdsCatsDeerDogsPup Moon PendantDolphinsHorsesWolvesElephantsTeddy BearsWolvesNEWNEW ChristmasNEW DisneyNEW DollsNEW ApparelNEW WatchesNEW FigurinesNEW Garden Birds
Customer Support
Make Online Payment
Home
Privacy & Cookie Policy
Privacy Policy
The Bradford Exchange Privacy & Cookie Policy
The Bradford Exchange are committed to complying with all relevant legislation on Data Protection and have published this guide to help you understand how and why The Bradford Exchange collects information from you, to whom such information is disclosed and what your rights are. If we make changes to this Policy we will notify you by updating this statement on our website. You can access our Website home page and browse our site without disclosing your personal data. However, when you register with The Bradford Exchange you will be asked to provide certain information about yourself.
Information that we collect from every visitor to our website
We collect anonymous cookie information about the site pages, items, stores and articles you view. This is not used with personally identifiable information (such as the name and address you give us when you place an order), but as aggregate information (group information) that helps us learn more about how people use and react to our site, thereby helping us to create a more enriching shopping experience for you. We store information about items you add to your cart so that your cart selections are not lost between visits, but we will not know who placed the items in the cart unless you log in or place an order.
Access, correct, or update your personal information
At The Bradford Exchange, we endeavour to act fairly and honestly in all our customer transactions. We keep complete and accurate records – should you wish to do so then it is your right to request information on the nature of the personal details we hold, how we collect it, how we use it and how we disclose it. If you wish to access, correct or update your personal information then simply contact us:
By Post: Bradford Exchange, PO Box 658, Stoke-on-Trent, ST4 4RT
By Phone: 0333 003 1545
By Email: customers@brad-ex.co.uk
Through our website: https://www.bradford.co.uk/contact-us
If you are unhappy with any response, please contact us using the above details and request to speak to the Data Protection Officer.
Collection and use of your personal information
We only collect personal information by lawful and fair methods. This means we are never intrusive when it comes to dealing with our valued customers. We collect information about our customers via order forms, media advertisement coupons, emails, questionnaires, telephone conversations and surveys.
All the data we hold is subject to General Data Protection Regulations, and is kept within the European Economic Area. Data is securely stored in alignment with best practices and for the standard statutory period required by EU Law, which is currently 10 years. We use the following personal data in our Legitimate Business Interests to process your order and to advertise our products:
Your Contact Details:
To produce and personalise (if required) your order.
To send your order to you and collect payment.
To keep you up to date with the progress of your order.
To ensure we contact you through your preferred means.
To write, email, text or call you to ensure all customer payments are made (under Contractual Legal Grounds).
Accurate Record Keeping
We keep a record of what you have bought, to enable us:
To ensure the guarantee periods are met.
To keep a record of your payments and instalment plans.
To send you information on other products we think may be of interest, based on previous purchases. We keep a record of previous offers we may have sent you to avoid sending the same offer again, which also helps reduce our environmental impact.
We keep a brief record of any correspondence or telephone calls we may have had with you so that we may always strive to help you with any question.
Automatic Data Processing
We automate our data processing to ensure efficient and accurate processing of your payment and dispatch of your order.
We use fair rules based on anonymised data analysis to offer a level of interest-free instalment payments. However as we do not have access to your personal financial situation, it is up to you to consider the affordability of any purchase you make.
In personal contact with our customers we always seek to offer the best service we can at all times and may review and refine any automated processing to improve our service and protect our legitimate business interests.
Third Party Services
We seek to maintain accurate contact details, including checking your contact details through commercially available records. For example, we check addresses against third party software to ensure that they are accurate.
We may, with your permission, perform a credit check before allowing you to purchase on our interest free instalments.
Please note that we may disclose personal customer information in response to legal process, such as in response to a court order, collection agency, law enforcement agency or a subpoena.
If you have experienced an issue with your data and we have been unable to solve the issue to your satisfaction, you have the right to complain to the Information Commissioners Office.
Disclosure of your personal information
From time to time, we use this information to offer you special promotional offers and exciting product opportunities that we deem to be of benefit or relevance to you as an individual. As such, the nature of personal information we collect is strictly relevant to the offer, product or service we are recommending or endorsing. This information is obtained using fair, honest and reputable methods only.
We may occasionally make your details available to other reputable marketers who believe they too are promoting products that are of interest to you. We work with Epsilon Abacus (registered as Epsilon International UK Ltd), a company that manages the Abacus Alliance on behalf of UK retailers. We also work with Conexance. Participating retailers of both Abacus and Conexance are active in the clothing, collectables, food & wine, gardening, gadgets & entertainment, health & beauty, household goods, and home interiors categories. They share information on what their customers buy. Epsilon Abacus analyses this pooled information to help the retailers understand consumers’ wider buying patterns. From this information, retailers can tailor their communications, sending people suitable offers that should be of interest to them, based on what they like to buy. However, under no circumstances will we pass on email addresses or telephone numbers.
If you prefer not to be included in such mailings or to receive offers from exterior marketers, please tick the appropriate box below in 'Marketing Permissions'.If you have experienced an issue with your data and we have been unable to solve the issue to your satisfaction, you have the right to complain to the Information Commissioners Office.
Security of your personal information
Protecting your personal privacy is our main concern. We take reasonable steps to ensure that all information we collect, use or disclose is accurate. It is either stored or eventually destroyed in a secured environment accessed only by authorised personnel.
Please note that our business support service providers may transfer your data outside the EEA. The transfer will take place in the presence of appropriate safeguards, including standard data protection clauses adopted by the EU Commission. If you would like more information, please contact us using the details above.
Secure shopping
We fully recognise the importance of secure shopping and the protection of your credit card details when purchasing from us or from our affiliated companies online. Our web server uses proven technology to encrypt your personal information, including debit or credit card numbers, names and addresses. When you place an order, the encryption process converts the characters you enter into code that is then securely transmitted over the Internet. This eradicates the potential accessibility of your personal financial data by outside individuals or agencies and all related fraud.
Marketing permissions
The Bradford Exchange will send you from time to time catalogues, special offers and promotions by post, email, SMS and phone.
If you do not wish to receive any further email messages from us, (if you unsubscribe we will not be able to send you preview details before anyone else) please contact us here.
If you do not wish to receive any further posted mailings from us, please contact us here.
If you do not wish to receive any further offers via phone, please contact us here.
If you do not wish to receive any further offers via SMS, please contact us here.
If you do not wish to receive any further specially selected third-party offers by post, please contact us here.
Please write your name & address in the white space below & return this form in the envelope provided to return this form to Bradford Exchange, PO Box 658, Stoke on Trent, ST4 4RT.
You have the right to request changes to your Marketing Permissions at any time, to see any information we hold about you and to request we delete any data. Please note, that we have a right to hold any data if we consider it is necessary to protect us from fraud or under our legal obligation to keep accurate financial records. If you request we delete your data, we may keep your contact details to prevent you from being added to our database in the future.
Please note that, as catalogues are printed in advance, it may take up to 6 weeks for the process to be complete. It may take up to 2 weeks for emails.
The Bradford Exchange Cookie Policy
Cookies are small text files that websites send to your computer. A cookie can be thought of as an Internet user's identification card. They let the website know when the user has returned. This lets the site bring up information relevant to that user, for example your name, past orders etc.
Unless you de-activate the cookies (see below for information on how to do this), our website will automatically serve cookies to your computer.
Cookies make the interaction between users and websites faster and easier. Without cookies, it would be very difficult for a website to allow a visitor to fill up a shopping basket or to remember the user's preferences or registration details for a future visit. The Bradford Exchange website uses cookies to allow customers to move from one part of the web site to another and to add items to the shopping basket without having to login repeatedly.
Cookies are not computer programs, and can't read other information saved on your hard drive. They cannot be used to disseminate viruses, or get a user's email address etc. They only contain and transfer to the website as much information as the users themselves have disclosed to that website. It is possible to opt out of cookies via your browser’s cookie settings, but if you do this you will not be able to shop from the Bradford Exchange website as the functions of the website are dependent on cookies. Please note that cookies are computer specific, so if you log on to any site from a different computer, the cookie settings on that computer will apply.
For further information about managing and disabling cookies on your computer see www.allaboutcookies.org/manage-cookies.
When you visit our sites, cookies are either served directly by us, or by our business partners. Here is a description of the different kind of cookies we use.
Essential cookies:
These cookies allow you to use the basic functionality of our website. For example, browsing our products, ordering and paying for items, checking your account information and viewing your order history.
Performance cookies:
They allow us to get to know how you use our website. They are used to analyse visitor information such as usage, visitor numbers and help us see how effective our advertising is and to understand what you like. We also use this information to help improve our website, make our marketing more relevant and improve the user experience.
Functionality cookies:
They allow us to provide additional functionalities to the website, and will retain some settings information. Whilst not essential for the functionality of our site, they do enable extra features that should improve your shopping experience.
Targeting Cookies:
We also use cookies to track visitors' interest in our products. We may use this to understand what most appeals to our customers so we can make our offers as appropriate as possible. Browsing behaviour is also used to create relevant banner advertising with product recommendations that we believe best relate to the items you viewed on our website. These banners are then served across other websites that you may visit, typically news sites, video sites and blogs. This process is called behavioural advertising and although the adverts are individually tailored to each visitor, all cookie data is anonymised and stored temporarily. Additionally, all banners of this type feature an "i" icon that provides more information from each advertising network and instructions on how to opt out.
We also use cookies to track visitors' interest in our products. We may use this to understand what most appeals to our customers so we can make our offers as appropriate as possible. Browsing behaviour is also used to create relevant banner advertising with product recommendations that we believe best relate to the items you viewed on our website. These banners are then served across other websites that you may visit, typically news sites, video sites and blogs. This process is called behavioural advertising and although the adverts are individually tailored to each visitor, all cookie data is anonymised and stored temporarily. Additionally, all banners of this type feature an "i" icon that provides more information from each advertising network and instructions on how to opt out.
We work with Sub2 Technologies Limited (Sub2) in relation to digital display advertising for our website. Sub2 works with third party advertising networks to let them know when to use cookies via our website. When cookies are used and stored on your device, data from these cookies is processed by Sub2 and by their third party advertising partners to serve you with advertising that is relevant to you, based on your previous browsing habits. The data is also used to limit the number of times you see an advertisement as well as to help measure the effectiveness of the advertising campaign. For further details about Sub2 and the third party advertising cookies that Sub2 facilitates via our website, please click here.
Version:
Data Privacy Policy UK – 05.04.19
Your Guarantee
The Best Guarantee for our Customers!
We provide the following no-quibble satisfaction guarantees:
Any non-personalised jewellery item: 120 days All coins: 14 days All other non-personalised products: 365 days We are unable to offer satisfaction guarantees on personalised products.
The satisfaction guarantee allows you to claim full refund or replacement providing the goods being returned to us are in saleable condition in their original packaging and earrings have not been worn or removed from their protective sleeve.
Our satisfaction guarantee does not affect your legal rights.
SHOP SAFE
SHOPS safe home ordering protection scheme
For more info please visit
www.shopspromise.com/consumers
For return policy check out our FAQ:Return Pollicy
Shopping at The Bradford Exchangeis 100% secure!
The Bradford Exchange uses a secure server and the industry-standard Secure Sockets Layer (SSL), an advanced encryption technology, to provide the highest level of security for your personal and financial information as it comes to us via the Internet. This state-of-the-art security technology means that all your sensitive information entered during checkout is encrypted to deter interception by third parties.
We're proud to have been formally certified. The GoDaddy.com Secured Seal is your trusted assurance that our Web site is authentic, that you are in direct communication with bradford.co.uk, and that all transactions are secured by SSL encryption.
